Bacteria are the oldest living organisms on the earth.
[AI] 细菌是地球上最古老的生物。
They've been here for billions of years.
[AI] 他们在这里已经有几十亿年了。
and what they are are single-celled microscopic organisms.
[AI] 它们是单细胞微生物。
So they're one cell
[AI] 所以他们是一个细胞
and they have this special property that they only have one piece of DNA.
[AI] 他们有一个特殊的属性，他们只有一段DNA。
So they have very few genes and genetic information
[AI] 所以他们只有很少的基因和遗传信息
to encode all of the traits that they carry out.
[AI] 对他们表现出的所有特征进行编码。
And the way bacteria make a living is that they consume nutrients
[AI] 细菌的生存方式是它们消耗营养
from the environment.
[AI] 来自环境。
they grow to twice their size. they cut themselves down in the middle.
[AI] 它们长到两倍大。他们在中间切了下来。
and one cell becomes two. and so on and so on.
[AI] 一个细胞变成两个。等等等等。
They just grow and divide and grow and divide -- so a kind of boring life.
[AI] 他们只是不断地成长，不断地成长，不断地分裂——这是一种无聊的生活。
except that what I would argue is that you have an amazing interaction with these critters.
[AI] 除了我想说的是你和这些生物有着惊人的互动。
I know you guys think of yourself as humans. and this is sort of how I think of you.
[AI] 我知道你们认为自己是人类。这就是我对你的看法。
This man is supposed to represent a generic human being.
[AI] 这个人应该代表一个普通人。
and all of the circles in that man are all the cells that make up your body.
[AI] 这个人的所有圆圈都是构成你身体的细胞。
There's about a trillion human cells that make each one of us who we are
[AI] 大约有一万亿个人类细胞组成了我们每个人
and able to do all the things that we do.
[AI] 能够做我们所做的一切。
But you have 10 trillion bacterial cells in you or on you
[AI] 但你体内或身上有10万亿个细菌细胞
at any moment in your life.
[AI] 在你生命中的任何时刻。
So. 10 times more bacterial cells than human cells on a human being.
[AI] 所以人类身上的细菌细胞是人类细胞的10倍。
And. of course. it's the DNA that counts.
[AI] 和当然重要的是DNA。
so here's all the A. T. Gs and Cs that make up your genetic code
[AI] 这是构成你遗传密码的所有A.T.Gs和Cs
and give you all your charming characteristics.
[AI] 给你所有迷人的特征。
You have about 30.000 genes.
[AI] 你有大约30000个基因。
Well. it turns out you have 100 times more bacterial genes
[AI] 好事实证明，你的细菌基因是你的100倍
playing a role in you or on you all of your life.
[AI] 在你的一生中扮演一个角色。
So at the best. you're 10 percent human; more likely. about one percent human.
[AI] 最好是这样。你百分之十是人类；更有可能。大约百分之一是人类。
depending on which of these metrics you like.
[AI] 取决于您喜欢这些指标中的哪一个。
I know you think of yourself as human beings.
[AI] 我知道你认为自己是人。
but I think of you as 90 or 99 percent bacterial.
[AI] 但我认为你是90%或99%的细菌。
(Laughter)
[AI] （众笑）
And these bacteria are not passive riders.
[AI] 这些细菌不是被动的骑士。
These are incredibly important; they keep us alive.
[AI] 这些都非常重要；他们让我们活着。
They cover us in an invisible body armor
[AI] 他们用隐形防弹衣掩护我们
that keeps environmental insults out so that we stay healthy.
[AI] 这就避免了对环境的侮辱，让我们保持健康。
They digest our food. they make our vitamins.
[AI] 他们消化我们的食物。他们制造我们的维生素。
they actually educate your immune system to keep bad microbes out.
[AI] 它们实际上教育你的免疫系统将有害微生物拒之门外。
So they do all these amazing things
[AI] 所以他们做了所有这些惊人的事情
that help us and are vital for keeping us alive.
[AI] 这有助于我们，对我们的生存至关重要。
and they never get any press for that.
[AI] 他们从来没有得到任何压力。
But they get a lot of press because they do a lot of terrible things as well.
[AI] 但是他们也因为做了很多可怕的事情而受到了很多媒体的关注。
So there's all kinds of bacteria on the earth
[AI] 地球上有各种各样的细菌
that have no business being in you or on you at any time.
[AI] 在任何时候都与你无关。
and if they are. they make you incredibly sick.
[AI] 如果是的话。它们让你恶心得要命。
And so the question for my lab is whether you want to think about all the good things that bacteria do
[AI] 所以我实验室的问题是，你是否想思考细菌所做的一切好事
or all the bad things that bacteria do.
[AI] 或者细菌做的所有坏事。
The question we had is: How could they do anything at all?
[AI] 我们的问题是：他们怎么能做任何事情？
I mean. they're incredibly small.
[AI] 我是说。它们非常小。
You have to have a microscope to see one.
[AI] 你必须用显微镜才能看到。
They live this sort of boring life where they grow and divide.
[AI] 他们过着这种无聊的生活，在那里他们成长和分裂。
and they've always been considered to be these asocial. reclusive organisms.
[AI] 他们一直被认为是不合群的。隐居的有机体。
And so it seemed to us that they're just too small
[AI] 所以我们觉得它们太小了
to have an impact on the environment
[AI] 对环境产生影响
if they simply act as individuals.
[AI] 如果他们只是作为个体行动。
So we wanted to think if there couldn't be a different way that bacteria live.
[AI] 所以我们想知道，细菌的生存方式是否能有所不同。
And the clue to this came from another marine bacterium.
[AI] 这条线索来自另一种海洋细菌。
and it's a bacterium called "Vibrio fischeri."
[AI] 这是一种叫做“费氏弧菌”的细菌
What you're looking at on this slide is just a person from my lab
[AI] 你在这张幻灯片上看到的只是我实验室的一个人
holding a flask of a liquid culture of a bacterium.
[AI] 盛有细菌液体培养物的烧瓶。
a harmless. beautiful bacterium that comes from the ocean.
[AI] 无害的。来自海洋的美丽细菌。
named Vibrio fischeri.
[AI] 名为费氏弧菌。
And this bacterium has the special property that it makes light.
[AI] 这种细菌具有发光的特性。
so it makes bioluminescence.
[AI] 所以它产生了生物发光。
like fireflies make light.
[AI] 就像萤火虫发光一样。
We're not doing anything to the cells here.
[AI] 我们没有对这里的细胞做任何事情。
we just took the picture by turning the lights off in the room.
[AI] 我们只是关了房间里的灯照了张相。
and this is what we see.
[AI] 这就是我们所看到的。
And what's actually interesting to us was not that the bacteria made light
[AI] 我们真正感兴趣的不是细菌发光
but when the bacteria made light.
[AI] 但是当细菌发光时。
What we noticed is when the bacteria were alone.
[AI] 我们注意到的是当细菌单独存在时。
so when they were in dilute suspension.
[AI] 所以当它们处于稀释悬浮液中时。
they made no light.
[AI] 他们没有发光。
But when they grew to a certain cell number.
[AI] 但当它们生长到一定数量时。
all the bacteria turned on light simultaneously.
[AI] 所有的细菌同时发光。
So the question that we had is: How can bacteria. these primitive organisms.
[AI] 因此，我们面临的问题是：细菌是如何生存的。这些原始生物。
tell the difference from times when they're alone
[AI] 告诉他们独处时的不同
and times when they're in a community.
[AI] 当他们在一个社区的时候。
and then all do something together?
[AI] 然后大家一起做点什么？
And what we figured out is that the way they do that is they talk to each other.
[AI] 我们发现他们这样做的方式就是互相交谈。
and they talk with a chemical language.
[AI] 他们用一种化学语言交谈。
So this is now supposed to be my bacterial cell.
[AI] 这应该是我的细菌细胞。
When it's alone. it doesn't make any light.
[AI] 当它孤独的时候。它不发光。
But what it does do is to make and secrete small molecules
[AI] 但它的作用是制造和分泌小分子
that you can think of like hormones.
[AI] 就像荷尔蒙一样。
and these are the red triangles. And when the bacteria are alone.
[AI] 这些是红色三角形。当细菌单独存在时。
the molecules just float away. and so. no light.
[AI] 分子就这样飘走了。等等。没有灯光。
But when the bacteria grow and double
[AI] 但是当细菌生长并加倍时
and they're all participating in making these molecules.
[AI] 他们都在参与制造这些分子。
the molecule. the extracellular amount of that molecule.
[AI] 分子。细胞外分子的数量。
increases in proportion to cell number.
[AI] 与细胞数量成比例增加。
And when the molecule hits a certain amount
[AI] 当分子达到一定量时
that tells the bacteria how many neighbors there are.
[AI] 这告诉细菌有多少邻居。
they recognize that molecule
[AI] 他们认出了那个分子
and all of the bacteria turn on light in synchrony.
[AI] 所有的细菌都同步发光。
And so that's how bioluminescence works --
[AI] 这就是生物发光的原理--
they're talking with these chemical words.
[AI] 他们在用这些化学词说话。
The reason Vibrio fischeri is doing that comes from the biology --
[AI] 费氏弧菌这样做的原因来自生物学--
again. another plug for the animals in the ocean.
[AI] 再一次海洋动物的另一个插头。
Vibrio fischeri lives in this squid.
[AI] 费氏弧菌生活在这只乌贼体内。
What you're looking at is the Hawaiian bobtail squid.
[AI] 你看到的是夏威夷短尾乌贼。
It's been turned on its back.
[AI] 它被翻了个身。
and what I hope you can see are these two glowing lobes.
[AI] 我希望你们能看到这两个发光的叶。
These house the Vibrio fischeri cells.
[AI] 这些是费氏弧菌细胞的所在地。
They live in there. at high cell number.
[AI] 他们住在那里。在高细胞数时。
That molecule is there. and they're making light.
[AI] 那个分子在那里。它们在发光。
And the reason the squid is willing to put up with these shenanigans
[AI] 而乌贼之所以愿意忍受这些恶作剧
is because it wants that light.
[AI] 因为它想要那盏灯。
The way that this symbiosis works
[AI] 这种共生关系的运作方式
is that this little squid lives just off the coast of Hawaii.
[AI] 这只小乌贼就住在夏威夷海岸附近。
just in sort of shallow knee-deep water.
[AI] 就在膝盖深的水里。
And the squid is nocturnal.
[AI] 乌贼是夜间活动的。
so during the day. it buries itself in the sand and sleeps.
[AI] 所以白天。它把自己埋在沙子里睡觉。
But then at night. it has to come out to hunt.
[AI] 但是在晚上。它必须出来打猎。
So on bright nights
[AI] 所以在晴朗的夜晚
when there's lots of starlight or moonlight.
[AI] 当有很多星光或月光的时候。
that light can penetrate the depth of the water the squid lives in.
[AI] 这种光线可以穿透鱿鱼生活的水深。
since it's just in those couple feet of water.
[AI] 因为它就在那两英尺深的水里。
What the squid has developed is a shutter that can open and close over the specialized light organ housing the bacteria.
[AI] 鱿鱼已经开发出一种快门，可以在容纳细菌的特殊光器官上打开和关闭。
And then it has detectors on its back
[AI] 然后它的背部有探测器
so it can sense how much starlight or moonlight is hitting its back.
[AI] 所以它能感觉到有多少星光或月光打在它的背上。
And it opens and closes the shutter
[AI] 它打开和关闭快门
so the amount of light coming out of the bottom.
[AI] 所以从底部出来的光的数量。
which is made by the bacterium.
[AI] 这是由细菌产生的。
exactly matches how much light hits the squid's back.
[AI] 和乌贼背上的光线完全匹配。
so the squid doesn't make a shadow.
[AI] 所以乌贼不会产生阴影。
So it actually uses the light from the bacteria
[AI] 所以它实际上利用了细菌发出的光
to counter-illuminate itself in an antipredation device.
[AI] 在防辐射装置中反发光。
so predators can't see its shadow.
[AI] 所以捕食者看不到它的影子。
calculate its trajectory and eat it.
[AI] 计算它的轨迹并吃掉它。
So this is like the stealth bomber of the ocean.
[AI] 这就像是海洋中的隐形轰炸机。
(Laughter)
[AI] （众笑）
But then if you think about it. this squid has this terrible problem.
[AI] 但是如果你仔细想想。这只乌贼有个可怕的问题。
because it's got this dying. thick culture of bacteria.
[AI] 因为它让这个快死了。细菌的浓培养。
and it can't sustain that.
[AI] 但它无法维持这一点。
And so what happens is. every morning when the sun comes up.
[AI] 所以发生的是。每天早晨当太阳升起的时候。
the squid goes back to sleep. it buries itself in the sand.
[AI] 乌贼又睡着了。它埋在沙子里。
and it's got a pump that's attached to its circadian rhythm.
[AI] 它有一个与昼夜节律相关的泵。
And when the sun comes up. it pumps out. like. 95 percent of the bacteria.
[AI] 当太阳升起的时候。它泵出。喜欢95%的细菌。
So now the bacteria are dilute. that little hormone molecule is gone.
[AI] 所以现在细菌被稀释了。那个小荷尔蒙分子消失了。
so they're not making light.
[AI] 所以他们不会发光。
But. of course. the squid doesn't care. it's asleep in the sand.
[AI] 但是当然乌贼不在乎。它在沙滩上睡着了。
And as the day goes by. the bacteria double.
[AI] 随着时间的流逝。细菌加倍。
they release the molecule. and then light comes on at night.
[AI] 它们释放分子。然后晚上灯就亮了。
exactly when the squid wants it.
[AI] 就在乌贼想要的时候。
So first. we figured out how this bacterium does this.
[AI] 所以首先。我们发现了这种细菌是如何做到这一点的。
but then we brought the tools of molecular biology to this
[AI] 但后来我们把分子生物学的工具带到了这里
to figure out. really. what's the mechanism.
[AI] 弄清楚。真正地机制是什么。
And what we found -- so this is now supposed to be my bacterial cell --
[AI] 我们发现的是，这应该是我的细菌细胞--
is that Vibrio fischeri has a protein.
[AI] 费氏弧菌有一种蛋白质。
That's the red box --
[AI] 那是红色的盒子--
it's an enzyme that makes that little hormone molecule. the red triangle.
[AI] 它是一种酶，能产生这种小激素分子。红色三角形。
And then as the cells grow. they're all releasing that molecule into the environment.
[AI] 然后随着细胞的生长。它们都在向环境中释放这种分子。
so there's lots of molecule there.
[AI] 所以那里有很多分子。
And the bacteria also have a receptor on their cell surface
[AI] 细菌的细胞表面也有一个受体
that fits like a lock and key with that molecule.
[AI] 这就像一把锁和一把钥匙一样与分子相匹配。
These are just like the receptors on the surfaces of your cells.
[AI] 这些就像细胞表面的受体。
So when the molecule increases to a certain amount.
[AI] 所以当分子增加到一定量时。
which says something about the number of cells.
[AI] 这说明了细胞的数量。
it locks down into that receptor
[AI] 它锁定在那个受体上
and information comes into the cells
[AI] 信息进入细胞
that tells the cells to turn on this collective behavior of making light.
[AI] 这告诉细胞开启这种集体的发光行为。
Why this is interesting is because in the past decade.
[AI] 这之所以有趣是因为在过去的十年里。
we have found that this is not just some anomaly
[AI] 我们发现，这不仅仅是某种反常现象
of this ridiculous. glow-in-the-dark bacterium that lives in the ocean --
[AI] 这太荒谬了。生活在海洋中的细菌在黑暗中发光--
all bacteria have systems like this.
[AI] 所有细菌都有这样的系统。
So now what we understand is that all bacteria can talk to each other.
[AI] 所以现在我们了解的是，所有的细菌都可以相互交谈。
They make chemical words. they recognize those words.
[AI] 他们制造化学单词。他们认出了那些词。
and they turn on group behaviors
[AI] 他们开启了群体行为
that are only successful when all of the cells participate in unison.
[AI] 只有当所有细胞都一致参与时，这才是成功的。
So now we have a fancy name for this: we call it "quorum sensing."
[AI] 所以现在我们有了一个别致的名字：我们称之为“群体感应”
They vote with these chemical votes.
[AI] 他们用这些化学投票。
the vote gets counted. and then everybody responds to the vote.
[AI] 计票。然后每个人都对投票做出反应。
What's important for today's talk is we know there are hundreds of behaviors
[AI] 今天的演讲重要的是我们知道有数百种行为
that bacteria carry out in these collective fashions.
[AI] 细菌以这些集体的方式进行。
But the one that's probably the most important to you is virulence.
[AI] 但对你来说最重要的可能是毒力。
It's not like a couple bacteria get in you and start secreting some toxins --
[AI] 这不像是一对细菌进入你体内并开始分泌一些毒素--
you're enormous; that would have no effect on you. you're huge.
[AI] 你是巨大的；那对你没有影响。你太大了。
But what they do. we now understand.
[AI] 但他们所做的。我们现在明白了。
is they get in you. they wait. they start growing.
[AI] 是他们让你上当了。他们等着。它们开始生长。
they count themselves with these little molecules.
[AI] 他们用这些小分子计算自己。
and they recognize when they have the right cell number
[AI] 当他们有正确的手机号码时，他们就能识别
that if all of the bacteria launch their virulence attack together.
[AI] 如果所有的细菌一起发动毒力攻击。
they're going to be successful at overcoming an enormous host.
[AI] 他们将成功地战胜一个庞大的东道主。
So bacteria always control pathogenicity with quorum sensing.
[AI] 因此，细菌总是通过群体感应来控制致病性。
So that's how it works.
[AI] 这就是它的工作原理。
We also then went to look at what are these molecules.
[AI] 然后我们也去看看这些分子是什么。
These were the red triangles on my slides before.
[AI] 这些是我之前幻灯片上的红色三角形。
This is the Vibrio fischeri molecule.
[AI] 这是费氏弧菌分子。
This is the word that it talks with.
[AI] 这就是它所用的词。
And then we started to look at other bacteria.
[AI] 然后我们开始研究其他细菌。
and these are just a smattering of the molecules that we've discovered.
[AI] 这些只是我们发现的一小部分分子。
What I hope you can see is that the molecules are related.
[AI] 我希望你们能看到的是，分子是相互关联的。
The left-hand part of the molecule is identical in every single species of bacteria.
[AI] 分子的左侧部分在每一种细菌中都是相同的。
But the right-hand part of the molecule is a little bit different in every single species.
[AI] 但是分子的右侧部分在每一个物种中都有一点不同。
What that does is to confer exquisite species specificities to these languages.
[AI] 这样做的目的是赋予这些语言精致的物种特性。
So each molecule fits into its partner receptor and no other.
[AI] 所以每个分子都与它的伙伴受体相匹配，而不是其他的。
So these are private. secret conversations.
[AI] 所以这些都是私人的。秘密对话。
These conversations are for intraspecies communication.
[AI] 这些对话是为了种内交流。
Each bacteria uses a particular molecule that's its language
[AI] 每个细菌都使用一种特定的分子，这是它的语言
that allows it to count its own siblings.
[AI] 这使得它可以计算自己的兄弟姐妹。
Once we got that far.
[AI] 一旦我们走了那么远。
we thought we were starting to understand that bacteria have these social behaviors.
[AI] 我们以为我们开始了解细菌有这些社会行为。
But what we were really thinking about is that most of the time.
[AI] 但我们真正想的是，大多数时候。
bacteria don't live by themselves. they live in incredible mixtures.
[AI] 细菌不是靠自己生存的。他们生活在令人难以置信的混合环境中。
with hundreds or thousands of other species of bacteria.
[AI] 与成百上千的其他种类的细菌。
And that's depicted on this slide. This is your skin.
[AI] 这张幻灯片上描述了这一点。这是你的皮肤。
So this is just a picture -- a micrograph of your skin.
[AI] 这只是一张照片，一张你皮肤的显微照片。
Anywhere on your body. it looks pretty much like this.
[AI] 你身体上的任何地方。看起来很像这样。
What I hope you can see is that there's all kinds of bacteria there.
[AI] 我希望你能看到那里有各种各样的细菌。
And so we started to think. if this really is about communication in bacteria.
[AI] 于是我们开始思考。如果这真的是关于细菌的交流。
and it's about counting your neighbors.
[AI] 这是关于计算你的邻居。
it's not enough to be able to only talk within your species.
[AI] 仅仅在你的种族内部说话是不够的。
There has to be a way to take a census
[AI] 一定有办法进行人口普查
of the rest of the bacteria in the population.
[AI] 人群中的其他细菌。
So we went back to molecular biology
[AI] 所以我们回到分子生物学
and started studying different bacteria.
[AI] 并开始研究不同的细菌。
And what we've found now is that. in fact. bacteria are multilingual.
[AI] 我们现在发现的是。事实上细菌是多种语言的。
They all have a species-specific system.
[AI] 它们都有一个物种特有的系统。
they have a molecule that says "me."
[AI] 他们有一个分子，上面写着“我”
But then running in parallel to that is a second system
[AI] 但与之并行运行的是第二个系统
that we've discovered. that's generic.
[AI] 我们已经发现了。这是通用的。
So they have a second enzyme that makes a second signal.
[AI] 所以他们有第二种酶产生第二种信号。
and it has its own receptor.
[AI] 它有自己的受体。
and this molecule is the trade language of bacteria.
[AI] 这个分子是细菌的商业语言。
It's used by all different bacteria.
[AI] 它被所有不同的细菌使用。
and it's the language of interspecies communication.
[AI] 这是种间交流的语言。
What happens is that bacteria are able to count
[AI] 结果是细菌能够计数
how many of "me" and how many of "you."
[AI] 有多少“我”和多少“你”
And they take that information inside.
[AI] 他们把这些信息放在里面。
and they decide what tasks to carry out
[AI] 他们决定执行什么任务
depending on who's in the minority and who's in the majority
[AI] 取决于谁是少数派，谁是多数派
of any given population.
[AI] 指任何给定的人口。
Then. again. we turned to chemistry.
[AI] 然后再一次我们转向化学。
and we figured out what this generic molecule is --
[AI] 我们弄清楚了这个普通分子是什么--
that was the pink ovals on my last slide. this is it.
[AI] 那是我最后一张幻灯片上的粉红色椭圆形。就是这样。
It's a very small. five-carbon molecule.
[AI] 这是一个非常小的房间。五碳分子。
And what the important thing is that we learned
[AI] 重要的是我们学到了什么
is that every bacterium has exactly the same enzyme
[AI] 每个细菌都有完全相同的酶
and makes exactly the same molecule.
[AI] 制造出完全相同的分子。
So they're all using this molecule for interspecies communication.
[AI] 所以他们都在利用这个分子进行物种间的交流。
This is the bacterial Esperanto.
[AI] 这是细菌世界语。
(Laughter)
[AI] （众笑）
So once we got that far.
[AI] 所以一旦我们走到了那一步。
we started to learn that bacteria can talk to each other with this chemical language.
[AI] 我们开始了解到细菌可以用这种化学语言相互交流。
But we started to think
[AI] 但我们开始思考
that maybe there is something practical that we can do here as well.
[AI] 也许我们在这里也可以做一些实际的事情。
I've told you that bacteria have all these social behaviors.
[AI] 我告诉过你，细菌有所有这些社交行为。
that they communicate with these molecules.
[AI] 它们与这些分子通讯。
Of course. I've also told you that one of the important things they do
[AI] 当然我也告诉过你他们做的一件重要事情
is to initiate pathogenicity using quorum sensing.
[AI] 是利用群体感应启动致病性。
So we thought:
[AI] 所以我们想：
What if we made these bacteria so they can't talk or they can't hear?
[AI] 如果我们让这些细菌不能说话或听不见呢？
Couldn't these be new kinds of antibiotics?
[AI] 这些难道不是新型抗生素吗？
And of course. you've just heard and you already know
[AI] 当然了。你刚刚听说，你已经知道了
that we're running out of antibiotics.
[AI] 抗生素快用完了。
Bacteria are incredibly multi-drug-resistant right now.
[AI] 目前，细菌对多种药物具有难以置信的耐药性。
and that's because all of the antibiotics that we use kill bacteria.
[AI] 这是因为我们使用的所有抗生素都能杀死细菌。
They either pop the bacterial membrane.
[AI] 它们要么破坏细菌膜。
they make the bacterium so it can't replicate its DNA.
[AI] 它们使细菌不能复制其DNA。
We kill bacteria with traditional antibiotics.
[AI] 我们用传统的抗生素杀灭细菌。
and that selects for resistant mutants.
[AI] 这就选择了抗性突变体。
And so now. of course. we have this global problem
[AI] 现在也是如此。当然我们有这个全球性的问题
in infectious diseases.
[AI] 在传染病方面。
So we thought. what if we could sort of do behavior modifications.
[AI] 所以我们想。如果我们可以做一些行为改变呢。
just make these bacteria so they can't talk. they can't count.
[AI] 让这些细菌不能说话。他们不会数数。
and they don't know to launch virulence?
[AI] 他们不知道如何发射毒力？
So that's exactly what we've done. and we've sort of taken two strategies.
[AI] 这正是我们所做的。我们采取了两种策略。
The first one is. we've targeted the intraspecies communication system.
[AI] 第一个是。我们瞄准了种内通讯系统。
So we made molecules that look kind of like the real molecules. which you saw.
[AI] 所以我们制造了看起来有点像真实分子的分子。你看到了。
but they're a little bit different.
[AI] 但是他们有点不同。
And so they lock into those receptors.
[AI] 因此它们锁定了这些受体。
and they jam recognition of the real thing.
[AI] 它们阻碍了对真实事物的识别。
So by targeting the red system.
[AI] 因此，以红色系统为目标。
what we are able to do is make species-specific. or disease-specific.
[AI] 我们所能做的就是使物种具有特异性。或疾病特异性。
anti-quorum-sensing molecules.
[AI] 反群体感应分子。
We've also done the same thing with the pink system.
[AI] 我们对粉色系统也做了同样的事情。
We've taken that universal molecule and turned it around a little bit
[AI] 我们把这个宇宙分子扭转了一点
so that we've made antagonists of the interspecies communication system.
[AI] 所以我们制造了种间通讯系统的对手。
The hope is that these will be used as broad-spectrum antibiotics
[AI] 希望这些药物能被用作广谱抗生素
that work against all bacteria.
[AI] 对所有细菌都有效。
And so to finish. I'll show you the strategy.
[AI] 就这样结束了。我会告诉你策略。
In this one. I'm just using the interspecies molecule.
[AI] 在这一个。我只是用了种间分子。
but the logic is exactly the same.
[AI] 但逻辑是完全相同的。
So what you know is that when that bacterium gets into the animal --
[AI] 所以你知道的是当细菌进入动物体内--
in this case. a mouse --
[AI] 在这种情况下。老鼠--
it doesn't initiate virulence right away.
[AI] 它不会马上产生毒力。
It gets in. it starts growing.
[AI] 它进来了。它开始生长。
it starts secreting its quorum-sensing molecules.
[AI] 它开始分泌其群体感应分子。
It recognizes when it has enough bacteria
[AI] 当它有足够的细菌时，它就能识别
that now they're going to launch their attack.
[AI] 现在他们要发动进攻了。
and the animal dies.
[AI] 动物死了。
And so what we've been able to do is to give these virulent infections.
[AI] 所以我们所能做的就是给这些致命的感染。
but we give them in conjunction with our anti-quorum-sensing molecules.
[AI] 但是我们把它们和我们的反群体感应分子结合起来。
So these are molecules that look kind of like the real thing.
[AI] 这些分子看起来有点像真的。
but they're a little different. which I've depicted on this slide.
[AI] 但是他们有点不同。我在这张幻灯片上描述过。
What we now know is that if we treat the animal with a pathogenic bacterium --
[AI] 我们现在知道的是，如果我们用致病细菌治疗动物--
a multi-drug-resistant pathogenic bacterium --
[AI] 一株多药耐药的病原菌--
in the same time we give our anti-quorum-sensing molecule.
[AI] 同时，我们给出了我们的反群体感应分子。
in fact. the animal lives.
[AI] 事实上动物活着。
And so we think that this is the next generation of antibiotics.
[AI] 所以我们认为这是下一代抗生素。
and it's going to get us around. at least initially.
[AI] 它会让我们四处走动。至少最初是这样。
this big problem of resistance.
[AI] 这是阻力的大问题。
What I hope you think is that bacteria can talk to each other.
[AI] 我希望你认为细菌可以相互交流。
they use chemicals as their words.
[AI] 他们用化学物质作为他们的语言。
they have an incredibly complicated chemical lexicon
[AI] 他们有一个极其复杂的化学词汇
that we're just now starting to learn about.
[AI] 我们现在才开始了解。
Of course. what that allows bacteria to do is to be multicellular.
[AI] 当然细菌的功能是多细胞的。
So in the spirit of TED.
[AI] 所以本着TED的精神。
they're doing things together because it makes a difference.
[AI] 他们在一起做事，因为这会带来不同。
What happens is that bacteria have these collective behaviors.
[AI] 发生的是细菌有这些集体行为。
and they can carry out tasks
[AI] 他们可以执行任务
that they could never accomplish if they simply acted as individuals.
[AI] 如果他们只是以个人的身份行事，就永远无法实现这一目标。
What I would hope that I could further argue to you
[AI] 我希望我能进一步和你争论什么
is that this is the invention of multicellularity.
[AI] 这是多细胞性的发明。
Bacteria have been on the earth for billions of years;
[AI] 细菌在地球上已经存在了数十亿年；
humans. couple hundred thousand.
[AI] 人类。二十万。
So we think bacteria made the rules for how multicellular organization works.
[AI] 所以我们认为细菌为多细胞组织的运作制定了规则。
And we think by studying bacteria.
[AI] 我们通过研究细菌来思考。
we're going to be able to have insight about multicellularity in the human body.
[AI] 我们将能够洞察人体的多细胞性。
So we know that the principles and the rules.
[AI] 所以我们知道这些原则和规则。
if we can figure them out in these sort of primitive organisms.
[AI] 如果我们能在这些原始生物中找到它们。
the hope is that they will be applied
[AI] 希望它们能得到应用
to other human diseases and human behaviors as well.
[AI] 对其他人类疾病和人类行为也是如此。
I hope that what you've learned
[AI] 我希望你所学到的
is that bacteria can distinguish self from other.
[AI] 细菌可以区分自我和他人。
So by using these two molecules. they can say "me" and they can say "you."
[AI] 所以通过使用这两个分子。他们可以说“我”也可以说“你”
And again. of course. that's what we do.
[AI] 一次又一次。当然我们就是这么做的。
both in a molecular way. and also in an outward way.
[AI] 两者都是以分子的方式。而且是以一种外在的方式。
but I think about the molecular stuff.
[AI] 但是我想到了分子的东西。
This is exactly what happens in your body.
[AI] 这正是你体内发生的事情。
It's not like your heart cells and kidney cells get all mixed up every day.
[AI] 它不像你的心脏细胞和肾脏细胞每天都被搞混。
and that's because there's all of this chemistry going on.
[AI] 那是因为所有的化学反应都在进行。
these molecules that say who each of these groups of cells is
[AI] 这些分子表示这些细胞群中的每一个是谁
and what their tasks should be.
[AI] 以及他们的任务应该是什么。
So again. we think bacteria invented that.
[AI] 再说一遍。我们认为这是细菌发明的。
and you've just evolved a few more bells and whistles.
[AI] 你刚刚进化出了更多的铃铛和口哨。
but all of the ideas are in these simple systems that we can study.
[AI] 但是所有的想法都在这些简单的系统中，我们可以研究。
And the final thing is. just to reiterate that there's this practical part.
[AI] 最后一件事是。只是重申一下，这是实际的一部分。
and so we've made these anti-quorum-sensing molecules
[AI] 所以我们制造了这些反群体感应分子
that are being developed as new kinds of therapeutics.
[AI] 作为一种新的治疗方法正在开发中。
But then. to finish with a plug for all the good and miraculous bacteria
[AI] 但是后来。最后用一个塞子塞住所有好的和神奇的细菌
that live on the earth.
[AI] 他们生活在地球上。
we've also made pro-quorum-sensing molecules.
[AI] 我们还制造了亲群体感应分子。
So we've targeted those systems to make the molecules work better.
[AI] 因此，我们针对这些系统，使分子更好地工作。
So remember. you have these 10 times or more bacterial cells
[AI] 所以记住。你有10倍或更多的细菌细胞
in you or on you. keeping you healthy.
[AI] 在你身上还是在你身上。让你保持健康。
What we're also trying to do is to beef up the conversation
[AI] 我们还试图加强对话
of the bacteria that live as mutualists with you.
[AI] 和你共同生活的细菌。
in the hopes of making you more healthy.
[AI] 希望能让你更健康。
making those conversations better.
[AI] 让这些对话变得更好。
so bacteria can do things that we want them to do
[AI] 所以细菌可以做我们希望他们做的事情
better than they would be on their own.
[AI] 比他们一个人好。
Finally. I wanted to show you --
[AI] 最后我想让你看看--
this is my gang at Princeton. New Jersey.
[AI] 这是我在普林斯顿的帮派。新泽西州
Everything I told you about was discovered by someone in that picture.
[AI] 我告诉你的一切都是那张照片里的人发现的。
And I hope when you learn things. like about how the natural world works --
[AI] 我希望当你学到东西的时候。比如自然世界是如何运作的--
I just want to say that whenever you read something in the newspaper
[AI] 我只想说，每当你在报纸上看到一些东西
or you hear some talk about something ridiculous in the natural world.
[AI] 或者你听到一些关于自然界中一些可笑的事情的谈论。
it was done by a child.
[AI] 这是一个孩子做的。
So science is done by that demographic.
[AI] 因此，科学是由人口统计学来完成的。
All of those people are between 20 and 30 years old.
[AI] 所有这些人都在20到30岁之间。
and they are the engine that drives scientific discovery in this country.
[AI] 他们是这个国家推动科学发现的引擎。
And it's a really lucky demographic to work with. (Applause)
[AI] 这是一个非常幸运的群体。（掌声）
I keep getting older and older. and they're always the same age.
[AI] 我越来越老了。他们的年龄总是一样的。
And it's just a crazy. delightful job.
[AI] 这简直是一场疯狂的比赛。令人愉快的工作。
And I want to thank you for inviting me here.
[AI] 我要感谢你邀请我来这里。
it's a big treat for me to get to come to this conference.
[AI] 能来参加这次会议对我来说是一大乐事。
(Applause)
[AI] （掌声）
Thanks.
[AI] 谢谢
(Applause)
[AI] （掌声）